[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What classification is used for an alert that correctly identifies that an exploit has occurred?",
    "choices": [
      "false negative",
      "true positive",
      "true negative",
      "false positive"
    ],
    "answer": 1,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which type of analysis relies on predefined conditions and can analyze applications that only use well-known fixed ports?",
    "choices": [
      "deterministic",
      "probabilistic",
      "log",
      "statistical"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which tool is included with Security Onion that is used by Snort to automatically download new rules?",
    "choices": [
      "Sguil",
      "Wireshark",
      "PulledPork",
      "ELK"
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which tool included in Security Onion is an interactive dashboard interface to Elasticsearch data?",
    "choices": [
      "Sguil",
      "Zeek",
      "Kibana",
      "Wireshark"
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Which type of analysis relies on different methods to establish the likelihood that a security event has happened or will happen?",
    "choices": [
      "probabilistic",
      "statistical",
      "deterministic",
      "log"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which NIDS tool uses a signature-based approach and native multithreading for alert detection?",
    "choices": [
      "Snort",
      "Bro",
      "Zeek",
      "Suricata"
    ],
    "answer": 3,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What is the host-based intrusion detection tool that is integrated into Security Onion?",
    "choices": [
      "OSSEC",
      "Snort",
      "Sguil",
      "Wireshark"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What are three analysis tools that are integrated into Security Onion?",
    "choices": [
      "Snort",
      "Suricata",
      "Sguil",
      "Kibana",
      "OSSEC",
      "Wireshark"
    ],
    "answer": [2, 3, 5],
    "type": "multiple-choice-v2",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What function is provided by Snort as part of the Security Onion?",
    "choices": [
      "to view pcap transcripts generated by intrusion detection tools",
      "to generate network intrusion alerts by the use of rules and signatures",
      "to normalize logs from various NSM data logs so they can be represented, stored, and accessed through a common schema",
      "to display full-packet captures for analysis"
    ],
    "answer": 1,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which tool is a Security Onion integrated host-based intrusion detection system?",
    "choices": [
      "Wazuh",
      "Suricata",
      "Snort",
      "Zeek"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which tool would an analyst use to start a workflow investigation?",
    "choices": [
      "Sguil",
      "ELK",
      "Snort",
      "Zeek"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Which alert classification indicates that exploits are not being detected by installed security systems?",
    "choices": [
      "true negative",
      "false positive",
      "false negative",
      "true positive"
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "type": "multiple-choice",
    "category": "Evaluating Alerts"
  }
]
